
var quiz = {
"JS": [
 {
            "id": 1,
            "question": "A 35 year old woman is considered infertile after _________________ of trying to conceive.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "1 month",
                    "b": "2 months",
                    "c": "4 months",
                    "d": "6 months"
                }
            ],
            "answer": "6 months",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 2,
            "question": "In in vitro fertilization (IVF) is a simple cost effective procedure for infertile couples.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "True",
                    "b": "False"
                }
            ],
            "answer": "False",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 3,
            "question": "If a couple is infertile, this means the couple _____________________?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "will never be able to have children",
                    "b": "could not conceive after 12 months of unprotected sex",
                    "c": "should look into adoption",
                    "d": "All of the above"
                }
            ],
            "answer": "could not conceive after 12 months of unprotected sex",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 4,
            "question": "Which sexually transmitted disease can result in infertility in women?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "Human papillomavirus (HPV)",
                    "b": "Genital Herpes",
                    "c": "Pelvic Inflammatory disease",
                    "d": "All of the above"
                }
            ],
            "answer": "Pelvic Inflammatory disease",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 5,
            "question": "Women should avoid pregnancy for three months after discontinuing birth control pills.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "True",
                    "b": "False"
                }
            ],
            "answer": "False",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 6,
            "question": "_______________? Is a major factor for infertility in women.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "Age",
                    "b": "weight",
                    "c": "Anovulation",
                    "d": "All of the above"
                }
            ],
            "answer": "All of the above",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 7,
            "question": "Men and women are equally likely to have infertility problems?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "True",
                    "b": "False"
                }
            ],
            "answer": "True",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 8,
            "question": "Women who are trying to conceive should boost their intake of?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "Nickel",
                    "b": "Lycopene",
                    "c": "Potassium",
                    "d": "Folic acid"
                }
            ],
            "answer": "Folic acid",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 9,
            "question": "The most fertile days of a woman's cycle can vary from months to months.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "True",
                    "b": "False"
                }
            ],
            "answer": "True",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 10,
            "question": "Men do not experience age-related decrease in infertility.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "True",
                    "b": "False"
                }
            ],
            "answer": "False",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 11,
            "question": "At which stage of the uterine cycle does the menstrual phase occur?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "1-15 days",
                    "b": "5-14 days",
                    "c": "14-28 days"
                }
            ],
            "answer": "1-15 days",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 12,
            "question": "Where is gonadotrophin-releasing hormone produced?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "Anterior pituitary gland",
                    "b": "Posterior pituitary gland",
                    "c": "Hypothalamus",
                    "d": "Adrenal gland"
                }
            ],
            "answer": "Hypothalamus",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 13,
            "question": "At which stage in the uterine cycle does the secretory phase occur?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "1-5 Days",
                    "b": "5-14 days",
                    "c": "14-28 days"
                }
            ],
            "answer": "14-28 days",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 14,
            "question": "At which point in the menstrual cycle is a woman most fertile?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "1-5 days",
                    "b": "9-16 days",
                    "c": "17-21 days",
                    "d": "22-28 days"
                }
            ],
            "answer": "9-16 days",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 15,
            "question": "Which of the following is the primary source of progesterone in the later stage of pregnancy?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "Foetus",
                    "b": "Endometrium",
                    "c": "Corpus luteum",
                    "d": "Placenta"
                }
            ],
            "answer": "Placenta",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 16,
            "question": "Which of the following is the function of luteinizing hormone (LH)?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "formation and maintenance of the corpus luteum",
                    "b": "thinning of the graffian follicles membrane",
                    "c": "stimulation of follicle development",
                    "d": "A and B"
                }
            ],
            "answer": "A and B",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 17,
            "question": "Which of the following symptoms indicate that a woman is about to ovulate?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "Decrease in basal body temperature",
                    "b": "Increase in basal body temperature",
                    "c": "Thickening of cervical mucous",
                    "d": "Thinning of cervical mucous"
                }
            ],
            "answer": "Increase in basal body temperature",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 18,
            "question": "At which stage in the uterine cycle does the proliferative phase occur?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "1-15 days",
                    "b": "5-14 days",
                    "c": "15–28 days"
                }
            ],
            "answer": "5-14 days",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 19,
            "question": "Which of the following hormone is the corpus luteum responsible for producing?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "Oestrogen",
                    "b": "Progesterone",
                    "c": "Follicle stimulating hormone",
                    "d": "Luteinizing hormone"
                }
            ],
            "answer": "Progesterone",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 20,
            "question": "Where are luteinizing hormone (LH) and follicle stimulating hormone (FSH) produced?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "Hypothalamus",
                    "b": "Anterior pituitary gland",
                    "c": "Posterior pituitary gland",
                    "d": "Adrenal gland"
                }
            ],
            "answer": "Anterior pituitary gland",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 21,
            "question": "Which of the following are function of progesterone during menstrual cycle?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a": "It causes the endometrium to become more receptive to implantation of a fertilized ovum",
                    "b": "It inhibits the production of luteinizing hormone (LH) and follicle stimulating hormone (FSH) via negative feedback",
                    "c": "Increase in basal body temperature",
                    "d": "All of the above"
                }
            ],
            "answer": "All of the above",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
		{
            "id": 22,
            "question": "Which of the following statements are true about menstruation?",
            "options": [ 
			{ 
                "a": "In a normal 28 days menstrual cycle menstruation lasts approximately 3-5 days",
                "b": "During menstruation the entire endometrium is shed",
                "c": "A and D",
                "d": "During menstruation only the functional layer of the endometrium is shed, with the basal layer remaining intact"
             }      
			 ], 
			  "answer":"A and D",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 23,
            "question": "Which of the following is prevention of sexual transmitted infection?",
            "options": [ 
			{ 
                "a": "Abstinence",
                "b": "Use of condom",
                "c": "Get tested especially new relationship",
                "d": "Avoid multiple sexual partners",
                "e": "All of the above"
             }     
			 ], 
			  "answer":"All of the above",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 24,
            "question": "The following are among the phases of human sexual response cycle?",
            "options": [ 
			{ 
                "a": "Excitement phase",
                "b": "Plateau phase",
                "c": "Orgasm phase",
                "d": "Resolution phase",
                "e": "All of the above"
             }     
			 ], 
			  "answer":"All of the above",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 25,
            "question": "Which of the following is the term for the experience of persistent or recurrent delay in or absence of orgasm following normal sexual excitement which causes the individual marked distress or interpersonal difficulty?",
            "options": [ 
			{ 
                "a": "Dysfunctional orgasmic disorder",
                "b": "Aclimactic disorder",
                "c": "Female orgasmic disorder",
                "d": "Female climatic disorder"
             }       
			 ],
          "answer":"Female orgasmic disorder",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 26,
            "question": "Genital pains that can occur, before, during or after sexual intercourse, and can occur in both male and females are known as",
            "options": [ 
			{ 
                "a": "Dyspareunia",
                "b": "Dysmenorrhoea",
                "c": "Dyskinesia",
                "d": "Dyspraxia"
             }      
			 ], 
			  "answer":"Dyspareunia",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 27,
            "question": "The involuntary contraction of the perineal muscles surrounding the outer third of the vagina when vaginal penetration is attempted is termed?",
            "options": [ 
			{ 
                "a": "Perinealitis",
                "b": "Perivaginitis",
                "c": "Vaginitis",
                "d": "Vaginismus"
             }      
			 ], 
			"answer":"Vaginismus",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 28,
            "question": "A common drug treatment for sexual dysfunction is Viagra. What is the generic term for this?",
            "options": [ 
			{ 
                "a": "Sildenafil citrate",
                "b": "Diclofenac",
                "c": "Metronidazole",
                "d": "Fluoxetine"
             }       
			 ], 
			 "answer":"Sildenafil citrate",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 29,
            "question": "In men, erectile dysfunction is associated with high levels of which of the following?",
            "options": [ 
			{ 
                "a": "Testosterone",
                "b": "Prolactin",
                "c": "Estrogen",
                "d": "Prostaglandin"
             }      
			 ], 
			  "answer":"Prolactin",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 30,
            "question": "Female sexual arousal disorder is defined primarily in terms of a deficiency in a physical or psychological response, and as a result may be caused by a range of physical or psychological factors, including?",
            "options": [ 
			{ 
                "a": "Hormone imbalances",
                "b": "Diabetes",
                "c": "Medication being taken for other disorders",
                "d": "All of the above"
             }       
			 ], 
			 "answer": "All of the above",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 31,
            "question": "Sexual dysfunction is one category of disorders of sexuality and sexual functioning. The term sexual dysfunction refers to?",
            "options": [ 
			{ 
                "a": "Problems with the normal sexual response cycle",
                "b": "Sexual urges or fantasies involving unusual sources of gratification problems",
                "c": "An individual is dissatisfied with their own biological sex and have a strong desire to be a member of the opposite sex",
                "d": "Problems with unusual fantasies"
             }       
			 ], 
			 "answer": "Problems with the normal sexual response cycle",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 32,
            "question": "Sarcoma botryoides is a rare tumor of __________________ presenting as a grape-like mass with bleeding",
            "options": [ 
			{ 
                "a": "Adult",
                "b": "Young children",
                "c": "Old people",
                "d": "Infants"
             }       
			 ], 
			 "answer": "Young children",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 33,
            "question": "Williams operation is a plastic surgery for:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "The repair of the uterus",
                "b": "The repair of the cervix",
                "c": "The repair of the vagina",
                "d": "The repair of the vulva"
             }       
			 ], 
			 "answer": "The repair of the vagina",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 34,
            "question": "Pytalism (excessive salivation) may occur from:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "6 weeks",
                "b": "8 weeks",
                "c": "10 weeks",
                "d": "12 weeks"
             }       ], "answer": "8 weeks",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 35,
            "question": " ______________ hormone relaxes smooth muscles of the veins, results in sluggish circulation, causes valves to be more ineffective and varicosities occur.",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Testosterone",
                "b": "Androgens",
                "c": "Oestrogen",
                "d": "Progesterone"
             }       ], "answer": "Progesterone",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 36,
            "question": "Weight increases in pregnancy should not exceed:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "11-12kg",
                "b": "12-13kg",
                "c": "10-12kg",
                "d": "10-16kg"
             }       ], "answer": "10-16kg",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 37,
            "question": "In pregnancy the heart slightly enlarges to about 12% to meet the challenge of increased blood volume. The blood volume increases by:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "50%",
                "b": "60%",
                "c": "70%",
                "d": "80%"
             }       ], "answer": "50%",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 38,
            "question": "The placenta and the chorion are formed from:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Blastocyst",
                "b": "Blastula",
                "c": "Trophoblast",
                "d": "Cleavage"
             }       ], "answer": "Trophoblast",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 39,
            "question": "Slight pelvic pain may accompany ovulation known as:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Nagging pain",
                "b": "Referred pain",
                "c": "Transient pain",
                "d": "Mittelschmerz’s syndrome"
             }       ], 
			 "answer": "Mittelschmerz’s syndrome",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 40,
            "question": "The total blood loss of menstruation is about:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "70-100mls",
                "b": "50-100mls",
                "c": "90-100mls",
                "d": "30-100mls"
             }       ], "answer": "50-100mls",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 41,
            "question": "Hydatidiform mole is:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Proliferative cystic degradation of the chorionic villi",
                "b": "Proliferative cystic degradation of the amniotic villi",
                "c": "Proliferation of the placenta"
             }       ], "answer": "Proliferative cystic degradation of the chorionic villi",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 42,
            "question": "The elements of communication include all the following except;",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Sender",
                "b": "Context",
                "c": "Decoding",
                "d": "Noise or interference environment"
             }       ], "answer": "Noise or interference environment",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 43,
            "question": "The WHO described advocacy for health in:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "1999",
                "b": "2005",
                "c": "1995",
                "d": "1990"
             }       ], "answer": "1995",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 44,
            "question": "IEC are introduced in the concept of:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Community health prevention",
                "b": "Communication concept",
                "c": "Prevention and primary healthcare",
                "d": "None of the above"
             }       ], "answer": "Prevention and primary healthcare",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 45,
            "question": "The formulation of PHC development committees is part of;",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Community participation",
                "b": "Advocacy",
                "c": "Health education",
                "d": "All of the above"
             }       ], "answer": "All of the above",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 46,
            "question": "Which of the following is not among the factors that enhance the communication to be effective:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Conciseness",
                "b": "Consideration",
                "c": "Clarity",
                "d": "Convenience"
             }       ], "answer": "Consideration",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 47,
            "question": "The essence of prevention and control of locally endemic diseases in PHC is:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "To improve communication process",
                "b": "For immunization activities",
                "c": "To reduce morbidity and mortality effect",
                "d": "For community mobilization"
             }       ], "answer": "To reduce morbidity and mortality effect",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 48,
            "question": "Which of the following is not among the factors responsible for the spread of infectious diseases:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Common vehicle",
                "b": "Disease agent",
                "c": "Environment",
                "d": "Host"
             }       ], "answer": "Common vehicle",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 49,
            "question": "Sentinel disease surveillance:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Is called community-based surveillance",
                "b": "Involves the training of community members to detect and respond to diseases",
                "c": "Consists of collecting and analyzing data on certain diseases in selected health facilities",
                "d": "All of the above"
             }       ], "answer": "All of the above",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 50,
            "question": "Ward code mark for household numbering system in PHC activities should be only:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Four (4) digits",
                "b": "Two (2) digits",
                "c": "Three (3) digits",
                "d": "Five (5) digits"
             }       ], "answer": "Three (3) digits",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 51,
            "question": "District code mark for household numbering system in PHC activities should be only:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Two (2) digits",
                "b": "Five (5) digits",
                "c": "Four (4) digits",
                "d": "Three (3) digits"
             }       ], "answer": "Two (2) digits",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 52,
            "question": "The capacity of the urinary bladder in healthy adults is:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "300-400 mls",
                "b": "600-700 mls",
                "c": "800-900 mls",
                "d": "199-299 mls"
             }       ], "answer": "300-400 mls",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 53,
            "question": "The clinical importance of the oblique entry of the ureters in the bladder is to:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Prevent urethral stricture",
                "b": "Promote urine formation",
                "c": "Enhance micturition",
                "d": "Prevent backflow of urine"
             }       ], "answer": "Prevent backflow of urine",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 54,
            "question": "A person with chronic glomerulonephritis is advised to have one of the following checks regularly:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Blood pressure",
                "b": "Blood sugar",
                "c": "Serum sodium",
                "d": "Haematocrit"
             }       ], "answer": "Blood pressure",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 55,
            "question": "An involuntary loss of urine following a coughing episode is referred to as:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Urge incontinence",
                "b": "Overflow incontinence",
                "c": "Stress incontinence",
                "d": "Functional incontinence"
             }       ], "answer": "Stress incontinence",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 56,
            "question": "A client with fever and urinary urgency is asked to provide a urine sample for culture and sensitivity. The nurse should instruct the client to collect the specimen from the:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "First stream of urine",
                "b": "Middle stream of urine",
                "c": "Final stream of urine",
                "d": "Full volume of urine"
             }       ], "answer": "Middle stream of urine",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 57,
            "question": "Juxtaglomerular cells are involved in the secretion of:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "ADH",
                "b": "Angiotensin",
                "c": "Aldosterone",
                "d": "Renin"
             }       ], "answer": "Renin",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 58,
            "question": "Secretion of urine formation involves:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Reabsorption and transportation of nutrient to the peritubular capillary",
                "b": "Secretion of substances from the peritubular capillaries to the distal tubules",
                "c": "Filtration of blood from the renal artery to the glomerulus",
                "d": "Production of renin"
             }       ], "answer": "Secretion of substances from the peritubular capillaries to the distal tubules",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 59,
            "question": "The clinical manifestation of acute pyelonephritis include the following except:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Haematuria and haemoptysis",
                "b": "High blood pressure",
                "c": "Albuminuria and edema",
                "d": "Vomiting, headache, malaise"
             }       ], "answer": "Haematuria and haemoptysis",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 60,
            "question": "One of the following is not a constituent of dialysate",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Water",
                "b": "Electrolytes",
                "c": "Glucose",
                "d": "Protein"
             }       ], "answer": "Protein",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
		 {
            "id": 61,
            "question": "The main renal replacement therapies include the following except:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Kidney transplantation",
                "b": "Haemodialysis",
                "c": "Peritoneal dialysis",
                "d": "Nephrectomy"
             }       ], "answer": "Nephrectomy",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 62,
            "question": "The normal potassium level in the body is between:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "3.5-5.5",
                "b": "5.5-6.5",
                "c": "6.5-7.5",
                "d": "7.5-8.5"
             }       ], "answer":"3.5-5.5",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 63,
            "question": "Renal angiography is a procedure used to:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Visualize the kidney",
                "b": "Visualize the artery",
                "c": "Visualize the renal blood vessels",
                "d": "Visualize the bladder"
             }       ], "answer": "Visualize the renal blood vessels",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 64,
            "question": "The right kidney is usually lower than the left kidney by about:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "4 cm",
                "b": "1.5-2 cm",
                "c": "2.5-3 cm",
                "d": "5-6 cm"
             }       ], "answer": "1.5-2 cm",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 65,
            "question": "The hilum is the __________ medial structure of the kidney:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Circular",
                "b": "Concave",
                "c": "Convex",
                "d": "Triangular"
             }       ], "answer": "Concave",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 66,
            "question": "WHO produced its first list of essential drugs in the year:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "1975",
                "b": "1979",
                "c": "1977",
                "d": "1980"
             }       ], "answer": "1977",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 67,
            "question": "The national drug policy was introduced in Nigeria in the year:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "1981",
                "b": "1992",
                "c": "1991",
                "d": "1990"
             }       ], "answer": "1991",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 68,
            "question": "The following drugs were derived from plants except:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Atropine",
                "b": "Heparin",
                "c": "Nicotine",
                "d": "Quinine"
             }       ], "answer": "Heparin",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 69,
            "question": "The first pharmacology department in the University of Michigan, USA was founded in the year:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "1892",
                "b": "1890",
                "c": "1900",
                "d": "1891"
             }       ], "answer": "1890",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 70,
            "question": "All the following are social effects of addiction except:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Difficulty in tolerating frustration",
                "b": "Neglect of personal hygiene",
                "c": "Hallucination",
                "d": "Spends all on drugs"
             }       ], "answer": "Hallucination",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 71,
            "question": "A child weighing 15 kg is placed on amoxicillin injection 40 mg/kg body weight 8 hourly, what is the amount for a single dose?",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "150 mg",
                "b": "200 mg",
                "c": "120 mg",
                "d": "220 mg"
             }       ], "answer": "200 mg",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 72,
            "question": "Which of the following drugs has the highest potential for physical dependence?",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Opiate",
                "b": "Cocaine",
                "c": "Cannabis",
                "d": "Lysergic acid diethylamide"
             }       ], "answer": "Opiate",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 73,
            "question": "All the following are transcutaneous routes of drug administration except:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Otic",
                "b": "Sublingual",
                "c": "Rectal",
                "d": "Inhalation"
             }       ], "answer": "Rectal",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 74,
            "question": "A patient is placed on 10% dextrose 1 litre 8 hourly, the set delivers 15 drops/milliliter. What is the drop per minute?",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "32 dpm",
                "b": "31.25 dpm",
                "c": "29.8 dpm",
                "d": "31.15 dpm"
             }       ], "answer": "31.25 dpm",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 75,
            "question": "A patient is to be given morphine 12 mg intramuscularly, the stock ampule contains 15 mg in 1.5 mls. What amount will be given using a 2 ml syringe?",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "1.5 mls",
                "b": "2 mls",
                "c": "2.5 mls",
                "d": "1.2 mls"
             }       ], "answer": "1.2 mls",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 76,
            "question": "All the following are true about alkaloids except:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Names of alkaloids end in “ine”",
                "b": "White crystalline substances",
                "c": "Sour in taste",
                "d": "Insoluble in water"
             }       ], "answer": "Sour in taste",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 77,
            "question": "The following are examples of RAUWOLFIA alkaloids except:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Reserpine",
                "b": "Cavadine",
                "c": "Germerine",
                "d": "Caffeine"
             }       ], "answer": "Cavadine",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 78,
            "question": "The epidermis of the skin replenishes itself by a process called:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Colonization",
                "b": "Reconstruction",
                "c": "Keratinization",
                "d": "Differentiation"
             }       ], "answer": "Differentiation",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 79,
            "question": "Repeated or prolonged pressure on the skin tissue can result in the development of:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Telangiectasis",
                "b": "Capillary hemangioma",
                "c": "Dermatomal lesion",
                "d": "Decubitus ulcer"
             }       ], "answer": "Decubitus ulcer",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 80,
            "question": "A client has full thickness burns of about 65% area of the body including the chest area. After establishing a patent airway, which collaborative intervention is the priority for this client?",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Replacement of fluid and electrolytes",
                "b": "Prevention of contracture of the extremities",
                "c": "Monitoring of urine output hourly",
                "d": "Preparation to assist with escharotomy"
             }       ], "answer": "Prevention of contracture of the extremities",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 81,
            "question": "The presence of scar on a deep wound is usually noticed at one of the following phases of wound healing:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Inflammatory phase",
                "b": "Migratory phase",
                "c": "Proliferative phase",
                "d": "Maturation phase"
             }       ], "answer": "Maturation phase",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 82,
            "question": "A client diagnosed with acne vulgaris, which psychological problem is the priority of this client?",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Impaired skin integrity",
                "b": "Ineffective skin integrity",
                "c": "Body image disturbance",
                "d": "Knowledge deficit"
             }       ], "answer": "Body image disturbance",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 83,
            "question": "Which of the following clients would be at the highest risk of developing carbuncle?",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "The young male who is just beginning to shave",
                "b": "The female with fair complexion",
                "c": "The male who works in the gymnasium daily",
                "d": "A female diagnosed with diabetes mellitus"
             }       ], "answer": "A female diagnosed with diabetes mellitus",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 84,
            "question": "The nursing diagnosis most applicable to a patient with skin disorders is:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Risk for imbalanced nutrition",
                "b": "Ineffective tissue perfusion",
                "c": "Risk for infection",
                "d": "Impaired physical mobility"
             }       ], "answer": "Risk for infection",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 85,
            "question": "Which of the following chambers contain endolymphatic fluid?",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Scala vestibuli",
                "b": "Scala tympani",
                "c": "Scala media",
                "d": "None"
             }       ], "answer": "Scala media",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 86,
            "question": " __________ defined nursing as the science and practice that expand adaptive abilities and enhances personal and environmental transformation:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Virginia Henderson",
                "b": "Callista Roy",
                "c": "Florence Nightingale",
                "d": "Abraham Maslow"
             }       ], "answer": "Callista Roy",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 87,
            "question": "Florence Nightingale was born on and in:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "May, 1820 in Germany",
                "b": "May, 1820 in Italy",
                "c": "May, 1820 in London",
                "d": "May, 1820 in New York"
             }       ], "answer": "May, 1820 in Italy",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 88,
            "question": "Florence Nightingale's most famous contribution came during:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "World War I",
                "b": "World War II",
                "c": "Crimean War",
                "d": "Gulf War"
             }       ], "answer": "Crimean War",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 89,
            "question": "The following are the fundamental responsibilities of a nurse except:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Promoting health",
                "b": "Prevention of illness",
                "c": "Health caring",
                "d": "Alleviating suffering"
             }       ], "answer": "Health caring",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 90,
            "question": "The modern history of nursing started with the effort of:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Abraham Maslow",
                "b": "Florence Nightingale",
                "c": "C.J. MacCotler",
                "d": "Faye Abdallah"
             }       ], "answer": "Florence Nightingale",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 91,
            "question": "According to drive theory, needs that are essential for human survival are referred to as:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Physiological needs",
                "b": "Primary needs",
                "c": "Esteem needs",
                "d": "Security needs"
             }       ], "answer": "Physiological needs",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 92,
            "question": "The ethics of non-maleficence is associated with:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Confidence",
                "b": "Self-determination",
                "c": "Doing no harm",
                "d": "Truth telling"
             }       ], "answer": "Doing no harm",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 93,
            "question": "Alma Ata declaration is on:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "1978 'Health for all by the year 2000'",
                "b": "1978 'Health promotion in a global world'",
                "c": "1978 'Move towards a new public health'",
                "d": "1978 'Nursing and midwifery for primary health'"
             }       ], "answer": "1978 'Health for all by the year 2000'",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 94,
            "question": "Receptors that detect changes in PaCO2 are called:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Chemoreceptors",
                "b": "Nociceptors",
                "c": "pH receptors",
                "d": "Osmoreceptors"
             }       ], "answer": "Chemoreceptors",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 95,
            "question": "Hydrogen ions are normally eliminated from the body:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "By excretion in the urine",
                "b": "Through insensible perspiration",
                "c": "In expired air",
                "d": "Through liver detoxification"
             }       ], "answer": "By excretion in the urine",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 96,
            "question": "Thyroid hyperplasia is also known as:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Thyroid swelling",
                "b": "Goiter",
                "c": "Toxic goiter",
                "d": "Endemic goiter"
             }       ], "answer": "Goiter",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 97,
            "question": "The most common cause of thyroid hyperplasia is:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Cigarette smoking",
                "b": "Infection",
                "c": "Goitrogenic agents",
                "d": "Iodine deficiency"
             }       ], "answer": "Iodine deficiency",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 98,
            "question": "Goitrogenic substances act by blocking the:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Action of thyroxine",
                "b": "Stimulation of thyroxine",
                "c": "Function of thyroxine",
                "d": "Production of thyroxine"
             }       ], "answer": "Production of thyroxine",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 99,
            "question": "Small doses of Lugol's iodine or potassium iodine solution are given if the goiter is due to:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Lack of enough sugar to use",
                "b": "Lack of sodium chloride",
                "c": "Enough iodine",
                "d": "Lack of iodine"
             }       ], "answer": "Lack of iodine",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 100,
            "question": "In managing patients with thyroid hyperplasia, nurses should note that T4 interacts with other medications such as:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Antihypertensives and anticoagulants",
                "b": "Hypoglycemic agents and diuretics",
                "c": "Oral hypoglycemic agents, anticoagulants and insulin",
                "d": "Anticoagulants, oral hypoglycemic agents and insulin"
             }       ], "answer": "Anticoagulants, oral hypoglycemic agents and insulin",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 101,
            "question": "In managing patient with thyroid hyperplasia, failure to ensure patient's adequate understanding may result in poor adherence to medications or:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Worsening the condition",
                "b": "Many complications",
                "c": "Damage to the thyroid gland",
                "d": "Increased anxiety level"
             }       ], "answer": "Worsening the condition",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 102,
            "question": "The parasitic worms responsible for elephantiasis include the following, except:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Wuchereria bancrofti",
                "b": "Brugia malayi",
                "c": "Brugia timori",
                "d": "Brugia manaw"
             }       ], "answer": "Brugia manaw",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 103,
            "question": "The most common parasite that causes elephantiasis is:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Brugia malayi",
                "b": "Brugia timori",
                "c": "Wuchereria bancrofti",
                "d": "Wuchereria sanga"
             }       ], "answer": "Wuchereria bancrofti",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 104,
            "question": "Filarial elephantiasis is the type that results from:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Lymphatic disorders",
                "b": "Infection",
                "c": "Mosquito bites",
                "d": "Lymphatic filariasis"
             }       ], "answer": "Lymphatic filariasis",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 105,
            "question": "Non-filarial elephantiasis is the type that results from conditions e.g.:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Malaria",
                "b": "Typhoid",
                "c": "Hepatitis",
                "d": "Podoconiosis"
             }       ], "answer": "Podoconiosis",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 106,
            "question": "All organisms, even the largest, start their life from a:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Zygote",
                "b": "Single cell",
                "c": "Morula",
                "d": "Nucleus"
             }       ], "answer": "Single cell",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 107,
            "question": "Cancer arises from abnormal and uncontrollable:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Mitosis",
                "b": "Cell cycle",
                "c": "Cell division",
                "d": "Nucleus"
             }       ], "answer": "Cell division",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 108,
            "question": "In cell cycle, resting phase where the cell left cycle and stopped dividing is:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "G1",
                "b": "G2",
                "c": "S phase",
                "d": "G0"
             }       ], "answer": "G0",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 109,
            "question": "In cell cycle, in which of the following phases does DNA replication occurs?",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "G0",
                "b": "G2",
                "c": "S phase",
                "d": "M phase"
             }       ], "answer": "S phase",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 110,
            "question": "A checkpoint mechanism which ensures that everything is ready to enter M phase is:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "G1",
                "b": "G0",
                "c": "G2",
                "d": "S phase"
             }       ], "answer": "G2",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 111,
            "question": "A benign tumour has all the following except:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Localized",
                "b": "Slower growth rate",
                "c": "Cell growth rate",
                "d": "Metastasis"
             }       ], "answer": "Metastasis",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 112,
            "question": "Malignant tumour has all the following features except:",
            "options": [ { 
                "a": "Not capsulated",
                "b": "High growth rate",
                "c": "Invades surrounding structures",
                "d": "Lack ability to invade neighboring structures"
             }       ], "answer": "Lack ability to invade neighboring structures",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        }
]
}
var quizApp = function () {
    this.score = 0;
    this.qno = 1;
    this.currentque = 0;
    this.answeredQuestions = [];
    this.totalque = quiz.JS.length;
    this.timer = 10800; 

    this.displayQuiz = function (cque) {
        this.currentque = cque;
        if (this.currentque < this.totalque) {
            $("#tque").html(this.totalque);
            $("#previous").attr("disabled", false);
            $("#next").attr("disabled", false);
            $("#qid").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].id + '.');
            $("#question").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].question);
            $("#question-options").html("");
            for (var key in quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0]) {
                if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0].hasOwnProperty(key)) {
                    $("#question-options").append(
                        "<div class='form-check option-block'>" +
                        "<label class='form-check-label'>" +
                        "<input type='radio' class='form-check-input' name='option' id='q" + key + "' value='" + quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] + "'><span id='optionval'>" +
                        quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] +
                        "</span></label>"
                    );
                }
            }
        }
        if (this.currentque <= 0) {
            $("#previous").attr("disabled", true);
        }
        if (this.currentque >= this.totalque) {
            $('#next').attr('disabled', true);
            for (var i = 0; i < this.totalque; i++) {
                this.score = this.score + quiz.JS[i].score;
            }
            return this.showResult(this.score);
        }
        this.highlightQuestionButtons();
    }

    this.showResult = function (scr) {
        $("#result").addClass('result');
        $("#result").html("<h1 class='res-header'>Total Score: &nbsp;" + scr + '/' + this.totalque + "</h1>");
        for (var j = 0; j < this.totalque; j++) {
            var res;
            if (quiz.JS[j].score == 0) {
                res = '<span class="wrong">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-remove c-wrong"></i>';
            } else {
                res = '<span class="correct">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-check c-correct"></i>';
            }
            $("#result").append(
                '<div class="result-question"><span>Q ' + quiz.JS[j].id + '</span> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].question + '</div>' +
                '<div><b>Correct answer:</b> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].answer + '</div>' +
                '<div class="last-row"><b>Score:</b> &nbsp;' + res +
                '</div>'
            );
        }
        this.updateSummary();
    }

    this.checkAnswer = function (option) {
        var answer = quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer;
        option = option.replace(/</g, "&lt;") //for <
        option = option.replace(/>/g, "&gt;") //for >
        option = option.replace(/"/g, "&quot;")
        if (option == quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer) {
            if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].score == "") {
                quiz.JS[this.currentque].score = 1;
                quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "correct";
            }
        } else {
            quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "wrong";
        }
        if (!this.answeredQuestions.includes(this.currentque)) {
            this.answeredQuestions.push(this.currentque);
        }
        this.updateSummary();
        this.highlightQuestionButtons();
    }

    this.changeQuestion = function (cque) {
        this.currentque = this.currentque + cque;
        this.displayQuiz(this.currentque);
    }

    this.updateSummary = function () {
        $("#answered").text(this.answeredQuestions.length);
        $("#unanswered").text(this.totalque - this.answeredQuestions.length);
    }

    this.startTimer = function () {
        var self = this;
        var timerInterval = setInterval(function () {
            self.timer--;
			var hours = Math.floor(self.timer / 3600); 
            var minutes = Math.floor((self.timer % 3600) / 60);
            var seconds = self.timer % 60;
            $("#timer").text(hours + ":" + (minutes < 10 ? '0' : '') + minutes + ":" + (seconds < 10 ? '0' : '') + seconds);
			

            if (self.timer <= 0) {
                clearInterval(timerInterval);
                self.showResult(self.score);
            }
        }, 1000);
    }

    this.createQuestionButtons = function () {
        var questionList = $("#question-list");
        for (var i = 0; i < this.totalque; i++) {
            var button = $('<button/>', {
                text: i + 1,
                id: 'qbtn' + i,
                click: function () {
                    var qIndex = parseInt($(this).text()) - 1;
                    quizAppObj.changeQuestion(qIndex - quizAppObj.currentque);
                }
            });
            button.addClass('btn btn-danger');
            questionList.append(button);
        }
    }

    this.highlightQuestionButtons = function () {
        for (var i = 0; i < this.totalque; i++) {
            var button = $('#qbtn' + i);
            if (this.answeredQuestions.includes(i)) {
                button.removeClass('btn-danger').addClass('btn-success');
            } else {
                button.removeClass('btn-success').addClass('btn-danger');
            }
        }
    }
}

var jsq = new quizApp();
var selectedopt;
jsq.displayQuiz(0);
jsq.startTimer();
jsq.createQuestionButtons();

$(document).ready(function () {
    $(document).on('change', 'input[name=option]', function () {
        selectedopt = $(this).val();
    });

    $('#next').click(function (e) {
        e.preventDefault();
        if (selectedopt) {
            jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
        }
        jsq.changeQuestion(1);
    });

    $('#previous').click(function (e) {
        e.preventDefault();
        if (selectedopt) {
            jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
        }
        jsq.changeQuestion(-1);
    });

    $('#submit').click(function (e) {
        e.preventDefault();
        jsq.showResult(jsq.score);
    });
});
